Just this morning, MiniMax released their brand-new large model, the MiniMax M3.
So in this video, we're going to put it to the test.
So, how good is this model's programming ability, really?
According to MiniMax,
It's the first model in China to bring together three cutting-edge capabilities.
including cutting-edge coding and Agentic capabilities.
and Agentic capabilities.
Plus, it boasts an ultra-long context window of 1 million tokens.
Plus, this model also supports multimodal capabilities.
So, in other words, it's not just about writing code.
but also process images and videos.
It can even directly control our computer desktop.
On SWE-bench Pro, a benchmark for measuring a model's programming capabilities,
on this benchmark,
MiniMax M3 scored 59 points.
It even surpassed GPT-5.5 and Gemini 3.1 Pro.
and Gemini 3.1 Pro.
This score is incredibly close to that of Opus 4.7.
In the Terminal-bench 2.1 benchmark,
MiniMax M3 scored 66 points,
This is just shy of Opus 4.7's score of 66.1.
On top of that, MiniMax M3 also utilizes a brand-new attention architecture.
called MSA, which stands for MiniMax Sparse Attention.
Which stands for MiniMax Sparse Attention.
And it's this very architecture that
that they were able to push the context window to a million tokens.
Plus, the computational cost per token
is only one-twentieth of the previous generation's.
To give you a fair and accurate picture,
So, just how good is this model's programming ability?
So, let's now jump into Claude Code.
Let's change Claude Code's base URL,
and the model ID to MiniMax M3's base URL.
and the model ID.
And just like that, we'll be using the MiniMax M3 model inside Claude Code.
Let's run some comprehensive tests.
Using the MiniMax M3 model in Claude Code is super easy.
you can then change the base URL for Claude Code,
and the model ID to the one for MiniMax M3.
Alright.
Alright, I've got it all set up here.
Alright, so now we can test out MiniMax M3 right here in Claude Code.
to put its programming capabilities to the test.
Alright, let's start by testing out MiniMax M3.
So, how good is its engineering-grade coding ability, really?
So, for our test, we're going to use the open-source project, OpenClaw.
The thing is, OpenClaw has a massive codebase.
And in the 'issues' section, you can see it's plagued with a ton of bugs.
Alright, let's put it to the test.
Let's pick one or two of the more representative bugs.
Let's have MiniMax M3 fix these bugs for us.
Let's see how MiniMax M3 handles bug fixing in Claude Code.
So, how effective is it actually at fixing bugs in Claude Code?
Alright, first, let's clone the OpenClaw repository to our local machine.
And it's cloning right now.
As you can see, the OpenClaw repository is massive.
So, with this massive project repository, OpenClaw,
Let's test its ability to fix a specific bug.
This is how we can truly put MiniMax M3's coding capabilities to the test.
Alright, let's start by running the 'init' command in Claude Code.
Let's have it initialize the project first.
to generate a memory file.
so it can get a better understanding of the OpenClaw project.
Alright, it's already generated the project file, CLAUDE.md.
Alright, let's head into OpenClaw's issues and find a bug or two.
and have MiniMax M3 fix it.
Alright, let's pick this issue in OpenClaw to test it out.
So, in Claude Code, we'll just type in the prompt.
And explain to me where the problem lies.
And right after that, we'll append the link to the issue.
And here, it's analyzing the root cause of the bug.
It also provides a breakdown of the steps to reproduce the bug.
So, with that in mind,
Alright, so now we can have it go ahead and fix this bug.
Then, we'll input the prompt.
Please fix this bug.
Make the changes as small and precise as possible.
Maintain consistency with the project's original code style.
Avoid introducing any unnecessary refactoring.
And now, let's just send it.
Let's have MiniMax M3 fix this bug for OpenClaw.
And what's really smart here is,
But it didn't jump right in to fix the bug.
Instead, it presents three different approaches.
Let's pick one of these approaches.
Because, as it mentioned, this will determine the scope of the changes.
Whether to introduce a new configuration switch.
And here, it's presented us with these three options.
For each option, it provides an explanation and specifies which files will be modified.
So, we'll go with the second option and have it do the fix.
And right here, we can see it starting to modify the code.
to fix this bug.
After waiting for about five minutes...
And there we have it, it's telling us the fix is complete.
And here's the code for the changes it made.
And for the files, it also provides a description of the behavioral changes.
So, just like that,
And just like that, we've successfully used MiniMax M3 within Claude Code.
and successfully fixed the issue with OpenClaw.
Now, let's crank up the difficulty even more.
A while back, the source code for Claude.Code was leaked.
So now, right within Claude.Code, we can use MiniMax M3 to analyze Claude.Code itself.
and analyze the source code that was leaked.
For instance, let's analyze Claude.Code and see
how Claude.Code handles telemetry for user data.
Alright, let's start by running the 'init' command.
This will give it a basic understanding of the Claude Code project.
And here, it's created a file called CLAUDE.md.
Alright, now we can enter our prompt.
Let's have it analyze the Claude Code project.
So, I'll just type in the prompt to analyze the project's code.
and find out how Claude Code does user telemetry.
And now, let's just send it.
And just like that,
So, we're in Claude Code,
Let's have the MiniMax M3 model analyze the over 500,000 lines of source code that were leaked from Claude_Code.
So, for something like this,
This is a great way to test MiniMax M3's ultra-long context window capability.
and its ability to understand code.
as well as its ability to analyze complex projects.
And just like that, it's finished the analysis.
And here, it's identified 6 exit endpoints from the source code.
Here's the specific file location.
And here are the line numbers in the file where the code is located.
And it also points out that this is hard-coded.
And it also provides four control switches here.
including how to turn these telemetry features on and off.
And then, right here, we have the device.
And there's also the identity fingerprint.
This includes the device ID, which remains permanent after the first startup.
In other words, a machine fingerprint.
As you can see, the analysis it provided is spot on.
And the MiniMax M3 model did it all in less than 5 minutes.
and precisely analyzed Claude Code's source code to pinpoint
these functions for user information telemetry
It pinpointed the exact files where this code is located.
and even the line numbers.
So, from what we've seen,
The MiniMax M3 model has a one-million-token context window.
When it comes to analyzing large codebases,
It can pinpoint the issue with great speed and accuracy.
So, here we have the MiniMax M3 that we're testing.
Its ultra-long context window and coding capabilities
Alright, let's continue our testing.
This time, let's try something a little more interesting.
We're going to take the entire 'Journey to the West' and put it into Claude Code.
and have MiniMax M3 generate a map for Journey to the West using front-end technologies.
Alright, so first, let's take a look at the prompt.
The prompt tells it that we'll be providing the text of 'Journey to the West'.
The prompt asks it to first read through and understand the entire text.
Then, using front-end technologies, it generates an interactive map of the Tang Monk's pilgrimage.
First, extract the main countries and locations mentioned in the text and list them out.
the demons encountered at each location, along with a summary of the key events that happened there.
The second step is to generate a visual route map.
Then, connect the locations in sequence with nodes to form the route.
Clicking on a node will bring up the demons you encounter at that location.
as well as other detailed requirements like a plot summary.
Visually, it should have a beautiful interface with a classical scroll-like style.
Now, let's go back to Claude Code and paste this prompt directly.
And then, right after that, we'll append the full file path to the novel, Journey to the West.
Alright, let's just send it right here.
It starts by using an efficient search method to pinpoint the key chapters.
So, for a test like this one,
This will test MiniMax M3's long-text comprehension capabilities.
as well as its coding capabilities.
Because it needs to work based on this novel,
and then generate a corresponding roadmap.
And here, we can see...
It has spawned multiple sub-agents that are now executing.
And we can also see the execution time for these agents.
as well as the tokens consumed.
And with that, the development is complete.
So, this is the visualization it generated. Let's open up the page and see how it looks.
Once we open it,
And here we have it.
So, here we have a route map with a classic scroll-like design.
And we can also scroll with the mouse to check out these nodes.
For instance, let's click on one of the nodes.
So let's click on Chang'an.
And with that click, this window pops up right here.
And this is the introduction to Chang'an.
and it lists the key events.
There are no demons here.
Alright, let's continue with our tests.
So, let's go ahead and click on Eagle Sorrow Gorge.
In Journey to the West,
This is Chapter 15.
The danger level is high.
And here we can see the key event.
He's summed it up very concisely.
Very accurate.
It also lists the main demons here.
It even lists the gains from the pilgrimage.
Alright, let's keep going.
So, let's take a look at the most dangerous one, the Lion-Camel Kingdom.
This covers chapters 74 to 77, with a 'Deadly' danger level.
And here are the three main demons.
And right here, we have the introduction for these three demons.
Now, let's talk about the danger level classification.
And for the Lion-Camel Kingdom, its classification is spot-on, really, really accurate.
So, with that in mind,
So, we're going to use the classic novel, Journey to the West.
Let's have the MiniMax M3 model
to generate a route map for Tang Sanzang's pilgrimage.
And we can click on each node to check it out.
So, from what we're seeing,
the MiniMax M3 model.
Its ability to understand long contexts is truly impressive.
Alright, let's move on to the next test.
This time, we're going to test out the MiniMax M3.
Let's test its multimodal capabilities.
So, in this folder,
I've placed three screenshots of Apple Music here.
Then, I'll have MiniMax M3 use these Apple Music screenshots as a reference.
to replicate it for us.
Let's see if it can actually replicate it.
A music player with an Apple Music-style interface.
Alright, let's take a look at the prompt we used.
I'll have it use these three Apple Music screenshots as a reference and build it with HTML and CSS.
and also use JS to create a high-fidelity replica of these UIs.
Now, let's go back to Claude Code, paste it in, and run it.
So, with something like this,
This will test out the multimodal capabilities of MiniMax M3.
and its front-end UI capabilities at the same time.
After waiting for a few minutes,
And here it has finished replicating Apple Music.
As you can see, once it's open, the UI looks almost identical to Apple Music.
And we can also scroll down.
And here are all the elements it generated for us.
And you can see there are images for all of them.
And here, we can also click on 'home'.
This is the home page.
And you can see what it's generated for us. The result is just fantastic.
It even generated the images for these album covers for us.
This UI is a really deep replica of Apple Music's interface.
I'd say the level of accuracy is at least 90%.
This just goes to show that MiniMax M3's visual capabilities are also incredibly powerful.
All we have to do is give it a screenshot.
and it can actually generate these interactive UIs for us.
Alright, let's put it to the test.
Let's have it use Three.js to develop a game that can be played in a browser.
a 3D Jurassic-style pickup truck dinosaur hunting game.
Let's open it up in the browser.
And here we have the start button.
Let's hit start.
So, as you can see, here's the pickup truck.
And here's the machine gun on the pickup truck.
And we can use the mouse to control its movement.
Alright, let's start it up and see how it looks.
As you can see, the effect is pretty good.
And there's a dinosaur approaching from the distance.
Let's try shooting it.
And as you can hear, the gunshot sound effect is also really well done.
And once the dinosaur is defeated, it just vanishes.
As you can see, it's pulled off this effect, and it's actually really impressive.
So, here's what we've tested.
Let's have it create an effect for a shooting game.
Alright, next up, let's have it develop a tomb-raiding adventure. The game should have that classic tomb raider vibe.
It's a first-person perspective.
The player is navigating through winding and twisting
exploring an ancient tomb filled with corridors and branching paths.
The light on the player's head illuminates a small area just ahead.
while the rest remains shrouded in darkness.
Alright, let's take a look at the cave exploration game it developed.
Let's click 'Start'.
And then...
As you can see, this is the first-person view.
And this area here is where the light is shining.
We can move backward and forward.
Here in the first-person view,
And we can see the pistol we're holding.
And now, let's try out the shooting test.
As you can see, it's firing.
Plus, you can see sparks flying when the bullets hit the wall.
Alright, let's keep exploring.
Alright, let's head around this corner and keep exploring.
And you can see there's a monster here.
And we shoot, landing a hit.
And it goes down.
Alright, let's move forward.
And now, let's head over to this spot.
There are monsters here.
We shoot.
And we hit it.
And here are some medkits.
Alright, let's keep moving forward.
Alright, you can see we've picked up these medkits.
Alright.
And now, I've been taken out by this monster.
Alright, let's start over.
As you can see, the game he developed is actually really well-made.
So, we won't keep testing this part any further.
Based on our extensive testing,
So, what we can see is
MiniMax M3 has a 1 million token context window,
and its ultra-long 1 million token context window
when it comes to analyzing large codebases,
and analyzing long texts, it truly has a significant advantage.
Plus, its multimodal and visual capabilities are also incredibly powerful. And most importantly, MiniMax M3...
And most importantly, MiniMax M3...
And its API pricing is way, way lower than the Claude series of models.
So, with all that said,
This means we can use MiniMax M3 in many scenarios as a replacement for the expensive Claude models.
Alright, that's all for this video.
Please feel free to like, follow, and share this video.
Thank you for watching.